Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
I can cut a thousand strands of hair
but I cannot sever the tangled threads of my mind.
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Go on.
We servants have a lowly status
and shouldn't touch such auspicious items.
We won't accompany Their Highnesses inside.
We wouldn't want to offend the gods.
That's true.
In such situations, it's better to be cautious.
Allow me.
Your Highness.
You haven't yet taken your prenatal tonic today.
Earlier you said it was too hot.
It's cooled down now.
It' will get cold if we wait longer.
Your Majesty.
We will all return momentarily.
Go on.
Her Majesty can indeed be virtuous
when she wants to be.
Before she didn't like Noble Consort Lumière.
Now she is willing to preserve the peace.
Don't talk disrespectfully about the Empress.
I thank Your Majesty for granting my wish,
personally tying a talisman pouch for me.
I am the Empress. It is my duty.
As a rule, it is your duty.
But in terms of feelings, Your Majesty most likely resents me.
I gifted you the Guanyin statue
hoping to bring peace to your heart.
The most important thing now is to
give birth to this heir for His Majesty.
Whether my child can survive is
entirely up to Your Majesty, not I.
Why is that?
Is that not true?
If Your Majesty so wishes, an heir can live.
But both mother and child can be ruined if their lives
run counter to Your Majesty's wishes.
For so many years,
Your Majesty has ruled the harem in this way.
I'm truly frightened
that if, one day, I offend Your Majesty,
I won't be able to save the baby in my belly.
Nonsense! You dare slander me?
Slander?
Let go!
Do you dare swear to the divine beings
that you've never harmed any imperial heirs?
Any concubines?
And that you've never harmed me?
I am the head of the harem.
Why should I swear at your command?
Let go!
You're scared, aren't you?
Why did Consort Austuce commit suicide?
Why did Concubine Paix lose her fertility?
Noble Lady Fuca's miscarriage.
And the loss of my first child.
You've done so many wicked things.
In your heart, you know full well!
How did this happen?
What happened to Her Highness?
What's happened to Her Highness?
Your Highness!
What's wrong?
Your Highness, what happened?
We need help!
Your Highness!
- Huan Huan!
- Your Majesty, Her Highness has fainted!
Call an imperial doctor!
- Yes!
- Go quickly!
Huan Huan!
Doctors!
Somebody get an imperial doctor!
Quickly get an imperial doctor!
Her Highness...
Your Highness!
Your Majesty, Her Highness is awake.
Noble Consort Lumière, you're awake.
Noble Consort Lumière, you should refrain from grief.
You will have another child someday.
I will have another child someday...
How can Your Majesty treat my child
as if he were a withered weed,
offering words of such faint comfort?
Your Majesty,
no matter how much you resent me,
why did you have to harm my child?
Ridiculous! When have I ever harmed your child?
Your Majesty... Your Majesty...
My child is gone,
not because I was careless.
It was Her Majesty...
She had a quarrel with me ...
and she pushed me.
Your Majesty, there are signs of Her Highness
being struck heavily on the stomach.
The imperial doctors can testify to that.
Someone must have pushed Her Highness forcefully.
Besides, the fetus in her belly has always been healthy.
Your Majesty must have felt the fetal movement often.
Were it not for the accident, a miscarriage would never have happened.
Empress,
only you and Noble Consort Lumière were inside the chamber!
Your Majesty...
You,
and you.
You two were right outside by the door.
Did you see anything?
The Imperial Consort and I were conversing outside the chamber.
We did not see anything, however...
However, the Imperial Consort and I did hear from inside the chamber
that Her Majesty and Noble Consort Lumière seemed to be having a dispute.
It's true, Your Majesty.
Her Majesty and Noble Consort Lumière were arguing.
We didn't dare to barge in.
I heard Noble Consort Lumière utter words like "afraid" and "terrified".
And Her Majesty told Noble Consort Lumière
to know her place and behave properly.
I did not make out anything else.
I saw with my own eyes, along with many pairs of eyes here,
When Noble Consort Lumière was injured and fainted,
only the Empress was at her side.
Your Majesty...
Her Majesty resents me for being favored by Your Majesty.
She believes that I harbor disrespect in my heart.
She rebuked me for it...
and pushed me in fierce anger.
Noble Consort Lumière was pestering and harassing me.
She grabbed my hand,
and I had to use strength to get myself away.
I did not push Noble Consort Lumière!
According to what you said,
it was Noble Consort Lumière who pushed herself over.
Your Majesty, I don't understand
why Noble Consort Lumière would pester Your Majesty.
Noble Consort Lumière is modest and prudent.
She follows the doctor's advice
and takes every bowl of the prenatal tonics on time.
For all these years, Noble Consort Lumière
has treated Your Majesty with diligence and deference.
Even if she displeased Your Majesty with certain words,
Your Majesty should be forgiving towards her.
Or at least give consideration to the imperial heir in her belly.
You said Noble Consort Lumière was pestering and harassing you.
How exactly did she disrespect you?
There were only the two of us in the chamber.
I know I can hardly defend myself even with a hundred mouths.
However, I was involved in this incident
because someone had their heart set on framing me.
You feel like you can't defend yourself even with a hundred mouths.
I feel that I can't understand this even with a hundred brains.
There were only the two of you inside and you had an argument.
I've seen with my own eyes
how you've always disliked Noble Consort Lumière.
But she has made many compromises
for the good of the Empress.
Your Majesty, I have no reason to harm Noble Consort Lumière.
For all these years that I've been managing the harem,
has Your Majesty ever seen me intentionally harm anyone?
You know it in your heart.
Your Majesty!
During the reign of Emperor Gaozong of Tang Dynasty,
Wu Meiniang was in high favor.
She wanted to take down Empress Wang,
so she strangled her own daughter in the cradle
and then accused Empress Wang of the murder.
My current predicament is the same as that of Empress Wang.
Your Majesty...
Her Majesty has placed her blame.
My own death would not be lamentable.
However, my child...
he did not even have the chance to open his eyes and see this world.
My child was innocent and died unjustly.
Longyue, why are you crying?
I did not see anything...
Come here.
What did you see? Tell your Imperial Father.
Imperial Father is here. You have nothing to fear.
Your Imperial Mother is here.
Tell Imperial Mother what happened.
Don't be afraid. Tell me.
Imperial Mother pushed Mother Lumière!
She pushed Mother Lumière!
Nonsense! You taught her to say that!
Say it! You taught her to defame me, didn't you!
Otherwise, it was you! Noble Consort Estime!
Your Majesty, you...
I'm wrongfully accused, Your Majesty.
This was an accident.
How could I have foreseen it and told Longyue to say that?
She is only six years old.
Is she capable of lying?
Besides, Noble Consort Lumière has just woken up.
Who could teach Longyue this lie?
Your Majesty!
I have been defamed just like Empress Wang.
I am not Emperor Gaozong.
I'm not fooled so easily!
You have always viewed Huan Huan as your mortal enemy.
You would be more than happy to eliminate her.
I swear in the names of my Ula-Nara ancestors,
I have never done anything to harm
Noble Consort Lumière's unborn child.
Why don't you take this oath in front of
the late Empress Dowager's Heavenly tablet?
The Empress has a vicious heart and cruelly harmed an imperial heir.
From this day onwards,
she is banned from stepping out of the Palace of Great Benevolence.
Su Peisheng.
Your Majesty.
Take her away.
Aye.
Your Majesty.
Please, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, pardon me for asking.
Is it true that the Empress...
You have served as an official for a long time.
It's only right that you have concerns.
I have thoroughly investigated this matter.
The Empress has no defense.
Your Majesty.
Although the Empress is not as benevolent
as the late Empress Première,
Her Majesty is not a malicious person.
There were many other incidents in the past...
It's not that I didn't have my suspicions.
I just did not want to bother.
But as for this incident,
the Empress has no credible defense.
But why would Her Majesty go to such lengths?
"Desire is a ravine one cannot fill."
“A greedy heart is never satisfied."
Now she's the Empress,
so she expects to be the legitimate Empress Dowager.
I entrusted the Third Prince to her.
And it caused her to form improper ideas.
Your Majesty is wise.
Yet, whoever succeeds the throne,
Her Majesty will always be the Imperial Mother Empress Dowager.
How could she willingly let her power slip from her grasp?
Then... how does Your Majesty plan to proceed?
I have heard rumors are arising in the palace.
Claiming that many children
died at Her Majesty's hands.
But rumors are just rumors in the end.
Just as only the Empress will always be the Empress.
Changing the head of the harem will have
a far-reaching impact.
My thoughts have not gone there yet.
A stable harem is a blessing to the Great Qing.
But I will ask the Empress to reflect on her wrongdoings,
and the punishment will be stern.
Your Highness, please have some tea and take a rest.
No matter how much I recite the sutras,
it cannot redeem my regret and shame for the child.
It was against Your Highness's own will.
The child is no more.
That is because his fate was only gently linked with that of Your Highness.
The most important matter at hand is that
although His Majesty has confined the Empress,
His Majesty did not announce any punishment.
The Empress is the foster mother of the Third Prince,
and a close relative of the late Empress Dowager.
For her to be pulled out by the roots,
we need to leave her with no one to rely on.
Mother, it's cold at night.
Kneeling can damage your health.
I have had this bird's nest soup made for you.
Please get up and have some.
I appreciate your filial heart.
I know that Mother is heartbroken over my unborn little brother.
My wife Fuca and I copied this sutra
to burn for him.
We wish he will soon enter the Pure Land.
You and Fuca have worked hard.
Mother, you're ill and I can't share your pain.
My heart is fuming with anxiety.
I know you're a filial son.
How has the Third Prince been?
I heard my Third Brother has been pleading with Imperial Father
for mercy on Imperial Mother.
But Imperial Father scolded him.
The Third Prince ... was brought up by the Empress.
Now that the Empress is punished,
you should associate with him less.
Yes.
The Third Prince and Imperial Mother depend on each other
"as close as teeth and lips."
I understand.
Of course,
each day with the Empress
gives the Third Prince a chance to succeed to the throne.
And each day with the Third Prince
gives the Empress another layer of support.
Yes, I understand, Mother.
Fourth Brother, you've always been the most diligent.
Even after marriage, you don't ever relax.
How do you have leisure to stand around today?
Today is Eighth Uncle's birthday.
I went to visit him in the prison of the Imperial Clan Court.
You were so bold as to visit Eighth Uncle?
You weren't afraid of being seen?
I wouldn't tell if anyone else asks.
But as your younger brother, I wouldn't keep secrets from you.
So ... Has Eighth Uncle been well?
How can he be well?
He's imprisoned, living worse than death.
Third Brother, there's something I've always wanted to tell you,
but I wonder if it's appropriate.
We're brothers. Don't feel like a stranger. Tell me.
After the fight for the throne,
Imperial Father had numerous clansmen locked up.
Whether Eighth Uncle or Fourteenth Uncle,
they were both as close to Imperial Father as "arms and legs."
If we can intercede on behalf of our uncles
and have Imperial Father's mercy bestowed on them,
that would preserve Imperial Father's reputation -
and a century from now, people won't say he
"destroyed his own arms and legs."
Also, this will bring peace to
the Empress Dowager under the Nine Springs.
Next month is the birth anniversary of the prior emperor.
If I get the chance that day,
I want to plead for Imperial Father's pardon on
Eighth Uncle and Fourteenth Uncle.
This is also the most filial tribute
to the late prior emperor and the Empress Dowager.
You have very noble intentions, Fourth Brother.
I'm so foolish, this didn't even cross my mind.
All right. If I get the chance on that day,
I'll certainly plead with Imperial Father for clemency.
Good.
Have some tea, Your Majesty.
His Majesty said you still can't go out yet.
Your Majesty has accompanied His Majesty for so many years...
but you were never confined.
Noble Consort Lumière enjoys high favor,
yet she's been confined many times.
I am the Empress. I can endure it.
[peace]
By the way, I heard that the Third Prince
interceded for Your Majesty
but invoked His Majesty's rebuke.
The Third Prince is truly stupid.
His priority right now should be protecting himself.
Your Majesty, the Third Prince was just being filial.
If a filial heart is misused, it can harm himself and others!
I can only hope that on the prior emperor's birth anniversary,
the Third Prince will meet my expectations.
As long as the Third Prince has a future,
all my suffering will not be in vain.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
You performed the task assigned well.
The prior emperor's ceremony was befitting.
Thank you for your praise, Imperial Father.
I saw the efforts you've made.
By the way, I heard that recently
you've visited your Eighth Uncle a few times.
Yes.
Eighth Uncle ... He is pitiful.
You do have benevolence residing in your heart.
Imperial Father, Eighth Uncle made a grave mistake.
Any punishment is justified.
It's just that all the sons of the prior emperor
are your brothers, like "arms and legs."
I think if the prior emperor were here,
he'd want to see filial piety and brotherly love.
What else?
And ...
And Fourteenth Uncle.
Imperial Father, Fourteenth Uncle is your brother by birth,
and the nearest uncle to me.
But he's been confined all this time.
When the prior emperor
confined Thirteenth Uncle,
you pleaded earnestly for him.
For the sake of the prior emperor,
what if you released Fourteenth Uncle?
I see you've been worrying about your uncles.
I dare not.
It's just that I heard ...
when the Empress Dowager was gravely ill,
she missed Fourteenth Uncle very much.
I was thinking
if Fourteenth Uncle were allowed to visit back then...
If your Fourteenth Uncle visited,
would the Empress Dowager's illness have been cured?
Do you think I'm unfilial to the Empress Dowager?
I don't dare.
You don't dare?
Weren't you just speaking of brotherly love?
I am not loving,
so no wonder my brothers don't respect me.
"When a father is loving, his son is filial."
I am not loving,
so there's no need for you to be filial?
That isn't what I meant.
Imperial Father.
I was thinking for your reputation.
Imperial Father,
whatever my uncles have done,
they are your brothers after all.
Whatever Imperial Mother has done,
she is still your wife.
I can withstand your momentary anger.
But I must think about your legacy down the centuries.
You've imprisoned your brothers and confined your wife.
The people are frightened -
what will your subjects think about you?
What will my subjects think?
It seems that
you want to be my master now.
I am your Imperial Father.
Yet you can't discern right from wrong
and vehemently defend guilty men and women.
In your eyes,
am I such a tyrant?
Or you cannot tolerate my rule
and can't wait to replace me?
I dare not, I dare not!
I dare not!
When I had just ascended the throne,
your Eighth Uncle and Fourteenth Uncle
disrespected me and found fault with everything I did.
You saw it all very well!
Yet today, you've switched sides and turned against me.
You're interceding for those who wished to harm me.
You've joined their "filthy breath" to disobey me.
As for why I confined your Imperial Mother,
it was not only for Noble Consort Lumiere's unborn son.
Your Imperial Mother has been pulling many threads
hoping to make you the Crown Prince!
Imperial Father...
So you still call me Father!
You are my eldest son.
Although you lack strength and competence,
I have always taught you and been forgiving towards you.
Heaven had no mercy.
I've made you become someone else's son!
If you want to plead for your Eighth Uncle,
why don't you be his son?
Imperial Father,
however angry you are,
you wouldn't disown your own son.
It was you who abandoned me as your father.
Not the other way around!
- Su Peisheng!
- Your Majesty.
Announce my decree:
Hongshi lacks the integrity to stay in the palace.
Since he is loyal to Yunsi,
he will become Yunsi's son.
Due to his crimes, Yunsi was stripped of his Imperial Belt
and his name was removed from the imperial pedigree.
Hongshi, as his son,
must also lose his Imperial Belt.
Immediately confiscate Hongshi's Imperial Belt.
His Eighth Uncle Lord Heng will foster and discipline him.
I no longer have this son!
Your Majesty...
What are you waiting for!
I obey.
Your Majesty!
Terrible news.
What is it now?
Third Prince, he...
He misspoke today?
It doesn't matter if His Majesty keeps me confined for now.
What matters is he still considers my sister,
and that gives me the chance to rise again like the sun.
His Majesty stripped the Third Prince of his Imperial Belt
and made him the son of Lord VIII!
What are you talking about?
The Imperial Clan Court has received the decree.
Nonsense!
The Third Prince is His Majesty's son.
How is this possible?
I wouldn't dare lie to Your Majesty.
The Third Prince spoke up for Lord XIV, Lord VIII, and Your Majesty.
His Majesty accused him of having ulterior motives.
Why all of a sudden ... did he speak up for those traitors?
All my years of painstaking efforts ... completely wasted...
Completely wasted!
Your Majesty, please think of a way to save the Third Prince!
It's no use!
His Majesty has always been hard-hearted.
He has cut off his paternal love by doing so....
Your Majesty,
if the Third Prince can't be the Crown...
Without the Third Prince,
there is still the Fourth Prince and Fifth Prince.
At the worst, there is the Sixth Prince.
The Sixth Prince...
Just like how Consort Austuce died.
Without Zhen Huan,
I can adopt the Sixth Prince.
Nothing else matters. Nothing!
As long as I am the Empress,
I can rise again like the sun behind the mountains!
It doesn't matter who gave birth!
As long as the child becomes mine,
I will be the one and only Empress Dowager!
Did you prepare what I asked for?
I did prepare it.
But Her Majesty isn't aware of this.
Shouldn't we report to her?
A suffering master indicates the servant's incompetence.
I've followed Her Majesty for so many years,
and she has never endured such indignity.
A lofty Empress is confined by a concubine's set-up?
It even caused Her Majesty to lose the Third Prince.
There can't be such injustice under Heaven.
But this is too risky. Should we fail,
our lives will be at stake.
It doesn't matter even if I lose my life.
As long as I can get rid of Noble Consort Lumière,
Her Majesty will be at peace from now on.
Give it to me.
Seventeenth Brother.
The ceremony for Imperial Father's birth anniversary is complete.
Whenever I remember our days with Imperial Father,
I feel deeply touched.
And so I shed tears today.
As a family, we are here to celebrate our brotherly bond.
I thank Your Majesty for your care.
I raise a toast to you.
Sit down, sit down.
We're one family. Don't stand on ceremony.
If Imperial Father was here
and saw you having a child on the way now,
he'd be delighted.
Everything I have is by the grace of Your Majesty.
I always feel grateful for the prior emperor's edification.
And you always show respect to your elder brother
while performing duties as a court official.
This is what's called
"harmony between brothers, as well as monarch and subject."
Yes.
Your little cousin is in aunty's belly.
Sixth Prince, do you like him?
I want a little sister.
What about Your Lordship?
Either is good.
Hongyan is very fond of Meng's child.
They seem to be fated.
It's natural to have a close affinity between cousins.
Hongyan, Hongyan.
Come to Mother to have some soup.
Don't disturb Lady Xian anymore.
I want my aunty to feed me. I want my aunty to feed me.
Sure, aunty will feed you.
Good boy.
Jingxian!
Jingxian, what's wrong?
Imperial doctors!
Call for the doctors now!
What's going on?
She was fine just now.
Yes.
She seems to be poisoned.
The food has been poisoned.
Imperial guards! Attend His Majesty!
Your Majesty, if Lady Xian was poisoned,
it's best if Your Majesty leaves for the Hall of Mental Cultivation.
Your Majesty.
I will not leave.
I'll stay to see whoever was so bold
as to assassinate her in my presence.
Move her to the back chamber first.
Yes.
Your Lordship...
I'm here. Right here.
Your Lordship.
Hurry.
Silver needle.
It's Crane's Red Crown.
Crane's Red Crown?
No. Her Ladyship's pregnancy is already full-term.
Quick. Go prepare the labor-inducing herbs.
Hurry. Go quickly.
Your Lordship. Please allow me to take Her Ladyship's pulse.
Fortunately, Her Ladyship only consumed
a small amount of the poisoned food
and still has strength for labor.
Your Lordship, please ease your mind.
We doctors will take care of everything.
I will go report back to His Majesty.
Go quickly.
Your Lordship.
Who wants to harm me?
Your Majesty,
Lord Consort Xian consumed Crane's Red Crown.
How can that be mixed into a palace banquet?
What was the last thing Lady Consort Xian consumed?
Your Majesty,
Lady Consort Xian had some of the Sixth Prince's soup.
Jinxi.
The silver turned black. This soup is poisonous.
Test this bowl too.
This soup is also poisonous.
Your Majesty, someone wants to kill Hongyan and me.
Lord Consort Xian's poisoning was unintended.
I am here.
Go.
Go investigate!
How was such filth added to the food for
Noble Consort Lumière and the Sixth Prince?!
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Lordship.
Am I about to die?
Nonsense. The imperial doctors are all here.
They're all here.
Your Lordship, it was because I got you drunk...
that gave me this child.
Don't talk about that now.
I will stay here with you.
I will always stay by your side.
Your Majesty, I have investigated thoroughly.
The dessert soup was made by the Imperial Kitchen
and brought here by the servants.
The maid who brought the soup for
Noble Consort Lumière and the Sixth Prince
said she met the maid Autumn
from The Palace of Great Benevolence.
Autumn did open up the box and asked what was inside.
Besides Autumn, the maid did not see anyone else.
I have already brought Autumn here.
Bring her in.
Yes.
Who ordered you to do this?
No one did.
It was my own doing.
Was it the Empress?
Her Majesty is still in confinement
and is not aware of my doings.
All of this was my own idea.
She's attempting suicide!
Your Majesty, why do you not believe Her Majesty?
Her Majesty is your wife! She loves you wholeheartedly.
Send her to the Department of Penalty
and punish her until she speaks the truth!
Your Majesty, Her Majesty is your wife!
The Empress of the Great Qing.
Your Majesty, why do you refuse to believe Her Majesty?
Carry her out.
Noble Consort Lumière, aren't you afraid of karmic retribution?
Noble Consort Lumière, you will die in hell!
You wretch, Noble Consort Lumière!
You wretch!
Your Majesty, it's a State Heir Prince.
But Lord Consort Xian was too weak after labor.
She was overcome by the poison and has just passed away.
Autumn.
Your Majesty.
Where's Autumn?
I haven't seen her around.
Even Jiang Fuhai is nowhere to be found.
Does Your Majesty want some water?
I can go pour some for you.
I'm asking you questions.
Why are you evading the question?
What else is there that I can't withstand?
Madam Autumn hasn't come back since yesterday.
Mr. Jiang has was also taken away last night.
How dare they!
How can they take away my servants
without sending half a word to me?
Your Majesty, the Department of Penalty
took them away per His Majesty's decree.
They said there was no need to inform Your Majesty.
What on earth has happened?
I also don't know.
I only heard Madam Autumn did not succeed
in poisoning Noble Consort Lumière
and killed Lord Consort Xian instead.
Are you still unwilling to tell the truth despite the whipping?
What is there to confess?
Her Majesty didn't do anything.
Do you really think His Majesty will believe you
if your tortures force a confession out of me?
Her Majesty will not spare you idiots once she regains power.
We received His Majesty's decree.
We won't spare any means to get the truth out of you.
Even if your body is made of steel,
I doubt you can withstand unrelenting instruments of torture.
Since you wouldn't tell us,
bring on the needle punishment!
How dare you!
Dare is not a question for us.
You need to ask if this needle dares to drill into your slim fingers.
Autumn is the most tight-lipped. She'll go first.
Let go of me! Let go of me!
That's what you get for not telling.
What about you?
You going to confess? Speak!
Hurry up and speak.
I wonder if the servants will confess.
I've heard the Brilliant Madams are even more capable
than the men in the Ministry of Justice.
But Autumn has always been the most loyal to the Empress.
I'm afraid she won't confess.
Even if she doesn't, there is still Jiang Fuhai.
And besides Jiang Fuhai,
Spring is also serving her time at the Department of Penalty.
Having them interrogated one after the other,
someone will eventually open up.
And once torn open,
everything they've hidden inside will be revealed.
My mind is finally at ease after hearing that.
This will become even more chaotic.
His Majesty must be struck at his most vulnerable spot.
Otherwise, if the Empress turns the tide around,
it won't be easy for us to reverse it.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Phoenix Taking Flight
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
The dreams I dimly recall;
The past I hardly remember,
amidst the autumn moons and the spring flowers.
Like the moon's reflection on water
or flowers seen through mist - floating and drifting.
The joyous sounds you brought;
The silence you left;
Changing faster than clouds can turn to rain.
Our minds resonated;
Our hearts beat in unison;
But we lost what we once possessed.
A poem to converse;
A melody to accompany;
A heart to bind to mine.
I hoped for endless longing and eternal promise,
but I’m left with only the flute and the zither.
With affection, I pleased;
With my heart, I committed;
With my arms, I embraced.
I desired to be remembered;
Desired to be cherished;
Why am I only hated and deceived?
My wish ran against my will.
Behold the mockery of destiny and the game of fate.
My unwavering love is gone
like flowers swept away in the wind.
Praying for a bright moon;
Praying for a rising sun;
Dreaming to bask in the spring breezes.
But the unsparing northern winds carry snow and rain
to destroy the aspirations of the plum tree.
A phoenix about to take flight rustles its wings
but the arc of its flight is unseen.
The phoenix tree sways in the wind,
shedding memories in the whispers of the falling leaves.